<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Urban Design on</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/urban-design/</link><description>Recent content in Urban Design on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/urban-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Low Cost Approach to Improving Pedestrian Safety with Deep Learning</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2019-02-06/raspberry-pi-deep-learning-traffic-tracker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2019-02-06/raspberry-pi-deep-learning-traffic-tracker/</guid><description>POST UPDATE: Since posting this, I've received a considerable amount of interest from individuals and local city governments from across the U.S. looking to get a better grasp on pedestrian data. Because of this, I spent some time building out a better algorithm and packaging it for easy use. I'm terrible with names, so for now it's simply "urban mobility tracker". If you can think of a better name, please let me know!</description></item><item><title>Do We Actually Need to Replace the Western Hills Viaduct?</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-11-29/western-hills-viaduct-spatial-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-11-29/western-hills-viaduct-spatial-analysis/</guid><description>Introduction and Background If you live in the Cincinnati area, by now you should have heard that the Western Hills Viaduct is in a fairly dire situation at the moment and calls for a replacement have reached an almost fevered pitch. While all this squealing for a replacement has been going on, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if a replacement was actually what Cincinnati needs? As it currently stands, it requires $1 million per year just to maintain and a replacement is expected to cost $335 million.</description></item><item><title>Mapping the Age of Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-02-15/the-age-of-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-02-15/the-age-of-cincinnati/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been really impressed by those &amp;ldquo;age of&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; maps that I see from time to time on the internet (see here, here, and here) so I thought I would give it a go this winter while I had a little free time. Between web scraping and actual map creation it ended up taking a little over a month to finish.
Click (here) to launch a full screen version of the map in a new window.</description></item></channel></rss>