<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Biking on</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/biking/</link><description>Recent content in Biking on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/biking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Quantified Bike Explore</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2021-06-17/the-quantified-bike-explore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2021-06-17/the-quantified-bike-explore/</guid><description>There are few things I find consistently more enjoyable than exploring my surroundings from the perspective of a bicycle. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s big cities or narrow country roads, there are details which can only be experienced from this perspective. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m biking around and come across something I know most people don&amp;rsquo;t get to experience, I&amp;rsquo;m often reminded of the following:
The world reveals itself to those who travel on foot. &amp;mdash; Werner Herzog Traversing the world by bike, silently under your own power, unencumbered by traffic, parking, or roads in general is a freedom second to none.</description></item><item><title>Long Tiny Loop: Attempt #1</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2021-04-03/long-tiny-loop-attempt-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2021-04-03/long-tiny-loop-attempt-1/</guid><description>Introduction I’m not exactly sure how I initially came across LongTinyLoop.com, but all I know is that it checks all the right boxes for me. It involves bikes, maps, algorithms, and it’s a competition! So what is Long Tiny Loop? It’s a challenge to travel the longest path, while both minimizing the overall footprint and not breaking the following rules (taken directly from here):
Neglecting to follow established roads and trails (e.</description></item><item><title>The Beautiful Commute: Visualizing one full year of bike commuting in Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2018-01-11/one-year-of-bike-commuting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2018-01-11/one-year-of-bike-commuting/</guid><description>Introduction 2017 was an interesting year in terms of my daily commute. Although I unfortunately own a car, I refuse to waste my life mired in a quagmire of traffic like some kind of suburban commuter. This means I&amp;rsquo;m biking everywhere, or taking transit. But not like one of those weird weekend warriors dressed head to toe in fluorescent lycra, more like hoodie and sweat pants. What made 2017 interesting was the fact that not only did I move around several times, but being apart of a rapidly growing tech startup, so did my office.</description></item><item><title>Biking from Cleveland to Montréal</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-12-22/bikepacking-cleveland-to-montreal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-12-22/bikepacking-cleveland-to-montreal/</guid><description>Earlier this summer after quitting my job I had a two week window before a mandatory bachelor party in Vegas which I was determined to fill with something good. Thinking of all the places I could visit within just two weeks, Montréal seemed like the best option. But since Montréal is only a single days car ride, I thought I could make it interesting by biking there. Seems doable right?</description></item><item><title>Cincy to Dayton and Back by Bike / My First Century!</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-08-31/cincy-to-dayton-bike-ride/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-08-31/cincy-to-dayton-bike-ride/</guid><description>Since I had some time off recently, I decided to finally try and bike to Dayton and back in one day. I bike everyday to and from work, so the idea of biking long distances simply to log miles isn’t that appealing to me. I’m not some suburban spandex wearing weekend warrior with a bike rack on my car. Still, the challenge has taunted me for a while and it sounded fun.</description></item></channel></rss>