<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>machine learning on Nathan Rooy</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in machine learning on Nathan Rooy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Word2vec from Scratch with Python and NumPy</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2018-03-22/word2vec-from-scratch-with-python-and-numpy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2018-03-22/word2vec-from-scratch-with-python-and-numpy/</guid><description>Introduction Since joining a tech startup back in 2016, my life has revolved around machine learning and natural language processing (NLP). Trying to extract faint signals from terabytes of streaming social media is the name of the game. Because of this, I'm constantly experimenting and implementing different NLP schemes; word2vec being among the simplest and coincidently yielding great predictive value. The underpinnings of word2vec are exceptionally simple and the math is borderline elegant.</description></item><item><title>Evolving Simple Organisms using a Genetic Algorithm and Deep Learning from Scratch with Python</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-11-30/evolving-simple-organisms-using-a-genetic-algorithm-and-deep-learning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-11-30/evolving-simple-organisms-using-a-genetic-algorithm-and-deep-learning/</guid><description>Introduction A few weeks ago I got pretty deep into a late night YouTube rabbit hole, and somewhere around evolving soft body robots, I came across this video (here). I'm not sure what if it was the peaceful background music or the hypnotizing motion of the dragonflies but I wanted to try and run the simulation on my local computer. After failing to find a GitHub repo for this, I decided to spend a few hours coding my own version in Python.</description></item></channel></rss>