<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathan.fun/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PTPX 2024</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-12-19/ptpx-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-12-19/ptpx-2024/</guid><description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve had my converted 3D printer / pen plotter up and running for most of the year now. It&amp;rsquo;s been working great, and so for one last challenge before the end of the year, I decided to participate in the annual pen plotter postcard exchange (PTPX). Started by Paul Butler and currently in its fifth season, PTPX is a &amp;ldquo;generalised secret santa&amp;rdquo; for plotter enthusiasts. Now the only challenge is to figure out what to plot!</description></item><item><title>How many slices of pizza did I just burn?</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-12-08/yams/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-12-08/yams/</guid><description>Earlier this summer, I was at the beach with my family and given we were at the beach and the weather was hot, the drumsticks were flowing like water. This inevitably led to questions like: how far do I need to run to burn off this drumstick? I know that at my weight (~185 lbs) and at a moderate pace (5:45 to 6:00), I burn about 125 calories per mile. So at 390 calories per drumstick, I need to log about 3 miles tomorrow in order to break even.</description></item><item><title>Biking from Nashville to Natchez</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-12-06/biking-natchez-trace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-12-06/biking-natchez-trace/</guid><description>I had never heard of the Natchez Trace before Aaron mentioned it to me earlier this summer. We were discussing what our early summer adventure should be, and Aaron (being a closet southerner) was pushing for it. This was actually ideal, because nowadays when it comes to stuff like this, I try to do as little research as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to be an adventure if you already know the route.</description></item><item><title>Pen plotting with a 3D printer</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-02-25/3d-printer-pen-plotter-conversion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2024-02-25/3d-printer-pen-plotter-conversion/</guid><description>Of all the things I&amp;rsquo;m not good at, it&amp;rsquo;s my lack of artistic ability that really steals the show. Anything involving &amp;ldquo;art&amp;rdquo; I can pretty much guarantee will result in disappointment. It&amp;rsquo;s a bummer, but it&amp;rsquo;s not all bad though. My artistic shortcomings are offset by a surplus in other areas like math and engineering. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s this imbalance that fuels my curiosity with the generative art community; especially the stuff involving pen plotters.</description></item><item><title>Porting windspeed.app to Go</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-11-19/windspeed-golang-serverless/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-11-19/windspeed-golang-serverless/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a small web service that adds weather details to Strava activities for the past year or so. It&amp;rsquo;s a super simple Python/Flask app that I actually just forked from Yuriy Volodin, made a couple changes, and deployed it with Railway.app. It&amp;rsquo;s been working without incident ever since.
The Railway.app experience has been great and I really like the platform, but it’s the wrong tool for the job. Even though there are about 200 active subscribers using the service, having a dedicated server that&amp;rsquo;s running continuously is a bit much.</description></item><item><title>3DPK: Hell Gate + Bronx Kill</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-08-27/3dpk-hell-gate-and-bronx-kill/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-08-27/3dpk-hell-gate-and-bronx-kill/</guid><description>If I had a nickel for every time I&amp;rsquo;ve circumnavigated Manhattan in my 3d printed kayak, I&amp;rsquo;d have 10 cents! But seriously though, there are so many interesting areas around here to explore it&amp;rsquo;s hard to decide where to go next. On this latest trip, I opted for the Hell Gate region of the East River and a small stream separating Randalls Island from the Bronx known as Bronx Kill.</description></item><item><title>Circumnavigating Manhattan with a 3D printed kayak</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-06-23/3dpk-circumnavigate-manhattan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-06-23/3dpk-circumnavigate-manhattan/</guid><description>Last month (May) the water was warm enough around here that I decided to go for it and see if my 3D printed kayak could survive a Manhattan circumnavigation. I learned from last summer that the ideal launch time is around one hour after low tide at the battery. With that in mind, I was leaving the 69th Street Transfer Bridge and making my way down the Hudson by 11am.</description></item><item><title>A visual book recommender</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-04-12/visual-book-recommender/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-04-12/visual-book-recommender/</guid><description>Introduction I have this long running conjecture that used book stores are superior to commercial book outlets (including Amazon) for discovering books. One of the reasons for this I think has less to do with a skewed explore/exploit strategy, and more to do with the way exploratory suggestions are sourced. I think financial pressure skews exploratory search suggestions towards oversampling newer books rather than older adjacent books. I get that though; oversampling newer books is a simple way to help combat the rich getting richer trap.</description></item><item><title>3D printing a full-size kayak</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-03-12/3d-printed-kayak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2023-03-12/3d-printed-kayak/</guid><description>Introduction Well, I&amp;rsquo;m nearly two years behind on posting this, but anyway, here we are. I started this thing right at the beginning of &amp;ldquo;lockdown&amp;rdquo; and at the time we had just left our place in Manhattan for a lake house in Ohio. With ample space and views of water I began to mentally reprioritize my side-project backlog. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I started dabbling with the idea of finally getting into 3D printing.</description></item><item><title>Turboshtein</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2022-11-03/turboshtein/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2022-11-03/turboshtein/</guid><description>Background I didn&amp;rsquo;t study computer science so the usefulness of bit shifts and other bitwise operations outside of low-level programming have always been a bit of a gray area for me. I finally gave in and decided to spend some time reading up on the subject and ended up implementing the Myers bit-vector algorithm1 for computing Levenshtein edit distance. I was fairly happy with the results so I wrapped the original C code in Python and uploaded it to PyPI.</description></item><item><title>Playing around with Dall·E 2</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2022-05-08/dall-e-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2022-05-08/dall-e-2/</guid><description>About a month ago OpenAI reached out to a few of my coworkers and myself and gave us early access to the new Dall·E 2 model. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with it in my freetime and wanted share some of the images. Here are some of my favorites along with the prompt I used to generate them.
"a monkey wearing a rocket pack flying over the jungle, digital art" "a tiger with fur made out of electricity, digital art"</description></item><item><title>Biking 118 non-intersecting miles in Brooklyn</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-10-09/long-tiny-loop-attempt-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-10-09/long-tiny-loop-attempt-2/</guid><description>Introduction Earlier this year, my goal was to get a Long Tiny Loop of score 30.0 or greater. I ended up falling short with a 29.75 which really annoyed me. Sooo, I set a new goal of scoring at least 40 by the end of the year. It took three attempts, I got a flat tire, and had to hop a barbed wire fence&amp;hellip; But I eventually got it.
Path Design Based on the design process from my first Long Tiny Loop attempt, I had a general idea of what I wanted to keep and what I wanted to improve for my second attempt.</description></item><item><title>The Quantified Bike Explore</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-06-17/the-quantified-bike-explore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-06-17/the-quantified-bike-explore/</guid><description>There are few things I find consistently more enjoyable than exploring my surroundings from the perspective of a bicycle. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s big cities or narrow country roads, there are details which can only be experienced from this perspective. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m biking around and come across something I know most people don&amp;rsquo;t get to experience, I&amp;rsquo;m often reminded of the following:
The world reveals itself to those who travel on foot. &amp;mdash; Werner Herzog Traversing the world by bike, silently under your own power, unencumbered by traffic, parking, or roads in general is a freedom second to none.</description></item><item><title>Long Tiny Loop: Attempt #1</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-04-03/long-tiny-loop-attempt-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-04-03/long-tiny-loop-attempt-1/</guid><description>Introduction I’m not exactly sure how I initially came across LongTinyLoop.com, but all I know is that it checks all the right boxes for me. It involves bikes, maps, algorithms, and it’s a competition! So what is Long Tiny Loop? It’s a challenge to travel the longest path, while both minimizing the overall footprint and not breaking the following rules (taken directly from here):
Neglecting to follow established roads and trails (e.</description></item><item><title>Making STL frontal area calculations easier</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-03-26/compute-stl-frontal-area/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-03-26/compute-stl-frontal-area/</guid><description>Introduction When working with aerodynamic properties such as drag, it&amp;rsquo;s common practice to normalize these values against some sort of reference area. For most ground vehicles with a pressure dominated drag contribution this ends up being the cross-sectional area as seen from the front (or projected onto the inlet plane). Most of the time, acquiring these values is pretty easy, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with some nice clean CAD files. Annoyingly though, sometimes all you have are the non-parametric, triangulated geometry (STL) files.</description></item><item><title>Improved routing for OSMnx with Taxicab</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-03-12/osmnx-openstreetmap-taxicab-routing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2021-03-12/osmnx-openstreetmap-taxicab-routing/</guid><description>Introduction If you’ve ever worked on the geospatial side of data science or just have a passion for maps and code, you’ve probably used OSMnx. It’s a solid Python package that fills the void between OpenStreetMap and NetworkX. I’ve used it for both work and personal projects, and I really like it a lot. The one thing though that I’ve always found lacking however is the routing functionality&amp;hellip; Let&amp;rsquo;s work through a simple example that demonstrates what I mean.</description></item><item><title>Biking from Cleveland to Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2020-09-17/bikepacking-cleveland-to-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2020-09-17/bikepacking-cleveland-to-cincinnati/</guid><description>The idea of biking from Cleveland to Cincinnati has been floating around in my adventure backlog for at least ten years now. It&amp;rsquo;s a three and a half hour drive that I made many times throughout college and as you&amp;rsquo;d expect, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty boring. The bike ride on the other hand was four days of beautiful scenery, small towns, and good food.
DAY 1: We started off Saturday morning from my brother's place in Tremont by first biking in the opposite direction for the first few miles.</description></item><item><title>Effective Simulated Annealing with Python</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2020-05-14/simulated-annealing-with-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2020-05-14/simulated-annealing-with-python/</guid><description>Introduction I use some form of optimization on a daily basis, whether it&amp;rsquo;s for work or personal projects. Something else I do on a daily basis is avoid simulated annealing. I&amp;rsquo;ve always associated simulated annealing with inefficiency. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s a global optimizer, but at what cost? In most situations I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to achieve optimal or near-optimal results in a substantially quicker time using various other methods (particle swarm, genetic/evolutionary, etc&amp;hellip;).</description></item><item><title>Visualizing One Hundred Years of Cincinnati Maps</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-11-27/georeferencing-historical-maps-of-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-11-27/georeferencing-historical-maps-of-cincinnati/</guid><description>Introduction A while back, someone posted on the Cincinanti subreddit an interesting mapping artifact. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to the question, but it got me thinking about what else has changed over time in Cincinnati in regards to maps and names? Luckly the Cincinnati Public Library Digital Archives has a wealth of information on just this topic.
I ended up downloading about a dozen maps ranging from as early as 1815 to as recent as 1900.</description></item><item><title>The Visual Similarity of Movie Posters</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-03-24/movie-poster-tsne/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-03-24/movie-poster-tsne/</guid><description>Recently this past winter my friends and I were trying to find something to watch on one of the major video streaming services and as as usual, we were drowning in decision paralysis. Page after page, and still nothing. After a certain point, all the movie covers began to blend together at which point we gave up. This got me thinking on the visual similarity of movie posters and the seemingly unoriginal designs most of them have&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>BlenderFOAM: Open-source Fluid Based Shape Optimization</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-03-05/blenderfoam-aerodynamic-shape-optimization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-03-05/blenderfoam-aerodynamic-shape-optimization/</guid><description>Introduction I was recently cleaning out my closet and came across an old hard drive labeled &amp;ldquo;grad school&amp;rdquo;. After plugging it in and exploring it for a few minutes, I came across all my old thesis stuff. Seeing how this was before I started using GitHub, I figured I would post it in hopes that someone else could get some use from it. Even though it uses older versions of both Blender and OpenFOAM, the results should still be perfectly acceptable given that the equations of fluid dynamics haven&amp;rsquo;t changed much in the last hundred years.</description></item><item><title>Finding the least efficient walking routes in Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-09-05/cincinnati-route-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-09-05/cincinnati-route-efficiency/</guid><description>A while back when I was working on my &amp;ldquo;age of cincinnati&amp;rdquo; map, one of the first things I noticed was how quickly we&amp;rsquo;ve changed the layout of our built environment. Nowhere are these non-traditional building patterns more apparent than the piecemeal development of suburbia.
Given the enormous subsidies that are required to create and maintain these suburban developments, it&amp;rsquo;s expected that their appearance would deviate from what a free market would provide.</description></item><item><title>A Low Cost Approach to Improving Pedestrian Safety with Deep Learning</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-02-06/raspberry-pi-deep-learning-traffic-tracker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2019-02-06/raspberry-pi-deep-learning-traffic-tracker/</guid><description>POST UPDATE: Since posting this, I've received a considerable amount of interest from individuals and local city governments from across the U.S. looking to get a better grasp on pedestrian data. Because of this, I spent some time building out a better algorithm and packaging it for easy use. I'm terrible with names, so for now it's simply "urban mobility tracker". If you can think of a better name, please let me know!</description></item><item><title>Word2vec from Scratch with Python and NumPy</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-03-22/word2vec-from-scratch-with-python-and-numpy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-03-22/word2vec-from-scratch-with-python-and-numpy/</guid><description>Introduction Since joining a tech startup back in 2016, my life has revolved around machine learning and natural language processing (NLP). Trying to extract faint signals from terabytes of streaming social media is the name of the game. Because of this, I&amp;rsquo;m constantly experimenting and implementing different NLP schemes; word2vec being among the simplest and coincidently yielding great predictive value. The underpinnings of word2vec are exceptionally simple and the math is borderline elegant.</description></item><item><title>Mapping the Chili Regions of Cincinnati [two year update]</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-02-01/chili-regions-of-cincinnati-updated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-02-01/chili-regions-of-cincinnati-updated/</guid><description>Roughly two yeas ago I wrote my first post on here, in which I created a voronoi diagram depicting the chili regions of Cincinnati. Each region corresponded to being closer to either Skyline Chili or Gold Star Chili. Since a voronoi tessellation is based off Euclidean distance (&amp;ldquo;as the crow flies&amp;rdquo;), its usefulness diminishes considerably when applied to street networks. Because we&amp;rsquo;re not yet traveling around using jetpacks, I modified the distance function to use something called network distance which is calculated using Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algorithm.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing one full year of bike commuting in Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-01-11/one-year-of-bike-commuting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2018-01-11/one-year-of-bike-commuting/</guid><description>2017 was an interesting year in terms of my daily commute. Although I unfortunately own a car, I refuse to waste my life mired in a quagmire of traffic like some kind of suburban commuter. This means I&amp;rsquo;m biking everywhere, or taking transit. But not like one of those weird weekend warriors dressed head to toe in fluorescent lycra, more like hoodie and sweat pants. What made 2017 interesting was the fact that not only did I move around several times, but being apart of a rapidly growing tech startup, so did my office.</description></item><item><title>Evolving Simple Organisms using a Genetic Algorithm and Deep Learning from Scratch with Python</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-11-30/evolving-simple-organisms-using-a-genetic-algorithm-and-deep-learning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-11-30/evolving-simple-organisms-using-a-genetic-algorithm-and-deep-learning/</guid><description>Introduction A few weeks ago I got pretty deep into a late night YouTube rabbit hole, and somewhere around evolving soft body robots, I came across this video (here). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what if it was the peaceful background music or the hypnotizing motion of the dragonflies but I wanted to try and run the simulation on my local computer. After failing to find a GitHub repo for this, I decided to spend a few hours coding my own version in Python.</description></item><item><title>Do We Actually Need to Replace the Western Hills Viaduct?</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-11-29/western-hills-viaduct-spatial-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-11-29/western-hills-viaduct-spatial-analysis/</guid><description>Introduction and Background If you live in the Cincinnati area, by now you should have heard that the Western Hills Viaduct is in a fairly dire situation at the moment and calls for a replacement have reached an almost fevered pitch. While all this squealing for a replacement has been going on, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if a replacement was actually what Cincinnati needs? As it currently stands, it requires $1 million per year just to maintain and a replacement is expected to cost $335 million.</description></item><item><title>Differential Evolution Optimization from Scratch with Python</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-08-27/simple-differential-evolution-with-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-08-27/simple-differential-evolution-with-python/</guid><description>Besides particle swarm optimization (PSO) which I touched on previously, differential evolution (DE) is one of my go-to favorites. Just like PSO, differential evolution falls within the evolutionary algorithms (EA) family. Differential evolution is very similar to genetic algorithms (GA) which are based on the principles of evolutionary biology such as mutation, crossover, and selection. The downside of genetic algorithms is that at their core, they are based on a bit level information structure.</description></item><item><title>Mapping the Age of Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-02-15/the-age-of-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2017-02-15/the-age-of-cincinnati/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been really impressed by those &amp;ldquo;age of&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; maps that I see from time to time on the internet (see here, here, and here) so I thought I would give it a go this winter while I had a little free time. Between web scraping and actual map creation it ended up taking a little over a month to finish.
Click (here) to launch a full screen version of the map in a new window.</description></item><item><title>Biking from Cleveland to Montréal</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-12-22/bikepacking-cleveland-to-montreal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-12-22/bikepacking-cleveland-to-montreal/</guid><description>Earlier this summer after quitting my job I had a two week window before a mandatory bachelor party in Vegas which I was determined to fill with something good. Thinking of all the places I could visit within just two weeks, Montréal seemed like the best option. But since Montréal is only a single days car ride, I thought I could make it interesting by biking there. Seems doable right?</description></item><item><title>Calculate the Distance Between Two GPS Points with Python (Vincenty’s Inverse Formula)</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-12-18/vincenty-formula-with-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-12-18/vincenty-formula-with-python/</guid><description>Recently the work I have been doing requires a higher degree of accuracy than which the haversine method I was using could provide. This prompted me to implement a Python version of the Vincenty&amp;rsquo;s inverse formula. Unlike the Haversine method (which I posted about previously) of directly calculating the great-circle distance between two points on a perfectly spherical Earth, Vincenty&amp;rsquo;s formulae is an iterative method which more realistically assumes Earth as an oblate spheroid.</description></item><item><title>Mapping out the Southern Cultural Divide in America</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-12-14/southern-cultural-divide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-12-14/southern-cultural-divide/</guid><description>I just finished the book American Theocracy by Kevin Phillips (which is a seriously good book!) but in one of the chapters they included a map showing the regions of the United States which identify as “Southern” versus “American”. The map was originally created by J.S. Reed in 1975. They achieved this by looking through the yellow pages and counting the businesses that included &amp;ldquo;Southern&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo;. From this data, they were able to create the contour map seen below (Google Books version here).</description></item><item><title>Creating parameterized 2D airfoils with quadratic Bézier curves and Python</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-09-14/airfoil-manipulation-via-bezier-curves-with-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-09-14/airfoil-manipulation-via-bezier-curves-with-python/</guid><description>Before any type of shape optimization can occur, the geometry needs to be parameterized (usually…). One of the easiest ways to accomplish this is through the use of Bézier curves. For this tutorial, we’re not going to manipulate an existing geometry, rather we’re going to generate the geometry from scratch using a series of connected Bézier curves called a composite Bézier curve.
A quadratic Bézier curve is defined using three control points.</description></item><item><title>Calculating the Distance Between Two GPS Coordinates with Python (Haversine Formula)</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-09-07/haversine-with-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-09-07/haversine-with-python/</guid><description>A lot of my posts recently have focused on the analysis of spatial data coming from either the GPS on my phone (collected through Strava) or geo-tagged tweets. Because of this I ended up writing my own Python module for calculating the distance between two latitude/longitude pairs. This is accomplished using the Haversine formula. While more accurate methods exist for calculating the distance between two points on earths surface, the Haversine formula and Python implementation couldn’t be any simpler.</description></item><item><title>Montréal’s Language Distribution According to Twitter…</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-09-01/language-of-montreal-according-to-twitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-09-01/language-of-montreal-according-to-twitter/</guid><description>Over the span of roughly eight months I was able to collect 1,116,442 tweets using the Tweepy Python library which facilitates easy access to the free Twitter API. If eight months sounds like a long time for only a ~1M tweets, that’s because the free Twitter API only gives access to roughly 1% of the total Twitter stream or “firehose”. Since saving the actual tweet goes against the user agreement, I only saved a lat/lon location and a language type within a single SQL database.</description></item><item><title>Cincy to Dayton and Back by Bike / My First Century!</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-08-31/cincy-to-dayton-bike-ride/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-08-31/cincy-to-dayton-bike-ride/</guid><description>Since I had some time off recently, I decided to finally try and bike to Dayton and back in one day. I bike everyday to and from work, so the idea of biking long distances simply to log miles isn’t that appealing to me. I’m not some suburban spandex wearing weekend warrior with a bike rack on my car. Still, the challenge has taunted me for a while and it sounded fun.</description></item><item><title>Particle Swarm Optimization from Scratch with Python</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-08-17/simple-particle-swarm-optimization-with-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-08-17/simple-particle-swarm-optimization-with-python/</guid><description>Particle swarm optimization (PSO) is one of those rare tools that’s comically simple to code and implement while producing bizarrely good results. Developed in 1995 by Eberhart and Kennedy, PSO is a biologically inspired optimization routine designed to mimic birds flocking or fish schooling. I’ll occasionally use PSO for CFD based aerodynamic shape optimization, but more often than not, it’s for a machine learning project. PSO is not guaranteed to find the global minimum, but it does a solid job in challenging, high dimensional, non-convex, non-continuous environments.</description></item><item><title>Mapping the White Castle/Krystal Divide</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-08-01/white-castle-krystal-divide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-08-01/white-castle-krystal-divide/</guid><description>Ahh White Castle. I’ve had a love/hate relationship with this place since college. Sometimes after a solid night of pillaging and conquering, nothing satisfies your hunger like those little square, steamed devil burgers. Give me a ten sack and life is good. Add in some tots and a side of ranch? Game over. Good night. As for Krystal, I had it once on the way to Panama for Spring Break. It was alright… And that’s the end of that story.</description></item><item><title>FiveThirtyEight: The Riddler (2016-July-08)</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-07-08/the-riddler/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-07-08/the-riddler/</guid><description>I hate puzzles, but for some reason I find the Riddler from FiveThirtyEight more addicting than Flavor Blasted Goldfish. Anyway, I decided to post my solution for this week. Below is the question:
The archvillain Laser Larry threatens to imminently zap Riddler Headquarters (which, seen from above, is shaped like a regular pentagon with no courtyard or other funny business). He plans to do it with a high-powered, vertical planar ray that will slice the building exactly in half by area, as seen from above.</description></item><item><title>Mapping out IHOP vs. Waffle House</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-03-23/ihop-vs-waffle-house/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-03-23/ihop-vs-waffle-house/</guid><description>So I had never actually been to a Waffle House until they put the one in across from Stab and Grab in Clifton. I have to say though, I’m questioning my loyalty to Toppers as my post-rage food source. The second time I went there it was all still so new to me that I splurged a bit and ordered “the left side of the menu”. It was the best meal of my life…</description></item><item><title>Dog Ownership in Cincinnati [map]</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-03-12/dog-ownership-in-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-03-12/dog-ownership-in-cincinnati/</guid><description>In Cincinnati, there&amp;rsquo;s a pomeranian named Michelle Obama. There’s also a Beagle named Sarah Palin, a German Shepherd named Obwan Kenobi, and a Pit Bull Terrier named Beyoncé. Actually there’s a total of six dogs named Beyoncé in Cincinnati. Bart Simpson? Check. How about Bruno Mars? Several. Willie Nelson, Willy Wonka, and Winston Churchill? Yes, yes, and yes. How about a Chihuahua named Taco Bell? Yes, face palm… Applesauce, Sriracha, Tabasco, Trumpet, Trombone, Toto, Tripod, Shampoo, and Tony Montana?</description></item><item><title>Mapping the Chili Regions of Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-02-03/chili-regions-of-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathan.fun/posts/2016-02-03/chili-regions-of-cincinnati/</guid><description>First post on my first blog ever! I created a voronoi diagram based off the locations of the two major chili chains in Cincinnati; Skyline and Gold Star. In simplest terms, the color correlates to which chili chain you’re closest to based off linear distance (not network distance). So whether your allegiance is with Skyline or Gold Star, the territories have been established!
Notes:
The restaurant latitude/longitude positions were scraped off Google Maps and imported into QGIS via a CSV layer.</description></item></channel></rss>