<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web scraping on</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/web-scraping/</link><description>Recent content in web scraping on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathanrooy.github.io/tags/web-scraping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mapping the Age of Cincinnati</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-02-15/the-age-of-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2017-02-15/the-age-of-cincinnati/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been really impressed by those &amp;ldquo;age of&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; maps that I see from time to time on the internet (see here, here, and here) so I thought I would give it a go this winter while I had a little free time. Between web scraping and actual map creation it ended up taking a little over a month to finish.
Click (here) to launch a full screen version of the map in a new window.</description></item><item><title>Mapping out the Southern Cultural Divide in America</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-12-14/southern-cultural-divide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-12-14/southern-cultural-divide/</guid><description>I just finished the book American Theocracy by Kevin Phillips (which is a seriously good book!) but in one of the chapters they included a map showing the regions of the United States which identify as “Southern” versus “American”. The map was originally created by J.S. Reed in 1975. They achieved this by looking through the yellow pages and counting the businesses that included &amp;ldquo;Southern&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo;. From this data, they were able to create the contour map seen below (Google Books version here).</description></item><item><title>Mapping the White Castle/Krystal Divide</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-08-01/white-castle-krystal-divide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-08-01/white-castle-krystal-divide/</guid><description>Ahh White Castle. I’ve had a love/hate relationship with this place since college. Sometimes after a solid night of pillaging and conquering, nothing satisfies your hunger like those little square, steamed devil burgers. Give me a ten sack and life is good. Add in some tots and a side of ranch? Game over. Good night. As for Krystal, I had it once on the way to Panama for Spring Break. It was alright… And that’s the end of that story.</description></item><item><title>Mapping out IHOP vs. Waffle House</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-03-23/ihop-vs-waffle-house/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-03-23/ihop-vs-waffle-house/</guid><description>So I had never actually been to a Waffle House until they put the one in across from Stab and Grab in Clifton. I have to say though, I’m questioning my loyalty to Toppers as my post-rage food source. The second time I went there it was all still so new to me that I splurged a bit and ordered “the left side of the menu”. It was the best meal of my life…</description></item><item><title>Dog Ownership in Cincinnati [map]</title><link>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-03-12/dog-ownership-in-cincinnati/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nathanrooy.github.io/posts/2016-03-12/dog-ownership-in-cincinnati/</guid><description>In Cincinnati, there&amp;rsquo;s a pomeranian named Michelle Obama. There’s also a Beagle named Sarah Palin, a German Shepherd named Obwan Kenobi, and a Pit Bull Terrier named Beyoncé. Actually there’s a total of six dogs named Beyoncé in Cincinnati. Bart Simpson? Check. How about Bruno Mars? Several. Willie Nelson, Willy Wonka, and Winston Churchill? Yes, yes, and yes. How about a Chihuahua named Taco Bell? Yes, face palm… Applesauce, Sriracha, Tabasco, Trumpet, Trombone, Toto, Tripod, Shampoo, and Tony Montana?</description></item></channel></rss>